Professional Profile:

Full-Stack Software Developer with a focus on both front-end and back-end technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, Java, and Spring Boot. Additionally, I have experience in managing both relational (SQL) and non-relational (NoSQL) databases, enabling me to produce comprehensive and efficient software solutions.

Educational Experience:

Software Engineering Project 1 (San José, 2023).

The project consisted of a web application for asset control, maintaining a record of a company's assets, their current and historical status, to ensure proper asset management. The technologies used were HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, and MongoDB.

Software Engineering Project 2San José, 2023)

The project involved developing a web application to improve the operational efficiency of Pet Inc. by automating reservation management, providing environmental condition monitoring for pets, and allowing pet owners to access real-time information about their animals. The technologies used were HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, C#, SQL Server, and JQuery.

Work Experience:

Customer Service Agent - Concentrix (March 2024 - Present)

- Interacting with customers through various channels, including calls, emails, and chats, ensuring compliance with established KPIs.
- Resolving complex customer issues using tools and support resources, ensuring a clear understanding of their requirements.
- Participating in activities to improve customer satisfaction and business performance.

Remote Dental Technician – SmileDirectClub (September 2020 – July 2023)

- Providing remote technical and clinical support to international customers.
- Resolving clinical and technical queries for customers in the United States, England, Canada, and Australia.
- Communicating effectively to explain treatment plans and provide technical support during treatment.

Education

- Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering (2023- currently enrolled)
 Universidad CENFOTEC
- Software Development Technician with Conversational English (January 2023 -March 2024)

Universidad CENFOTEC

- Scrum Fundamentals Certification (October 2023) https://www.scrumstudy.com/certification/verify?type=SFC&number=1001964
- Bachelor's Degree in Dentistry (2012-2021)
 Universidad de Costa Rica
- Colegio San Agustín, Panama City, Panama (2007 2012)
 Degrees Obtained: Commercial Expert and Bachelor in Science and Letters

Languages

Spanish: NativeEnglish: Advanced

Technical Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- Python
- JavaScript
- Java
- SQL
- MongoDB
- CosmoDB
- Angular
- .Net
- SpringBoot
- C#

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Problem-solving
- Analytical skills
- Effective communication
- Adaptability
- Innovation
- Responsibility
- Patience and perseverance
- Critical thinking

Link for GitHub: https://github.com/Dexfex19

Link for LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-echeverria-ortega-a878aa281